<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.13">
  <compounddef id="indexpage" kind="page">
    <compoundname>index</compoundname>
    <title>QGIS</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<sect1 id="index_1index_intro">
<title>Introduction</title>
<para> is a user friendly Open Source Geographic Information System (GIS) that runs on Linux, Unix, Mac OSX, and Windows. QGIS supports vector, raster, and database formats. QGIS is licensed under the GNU General Public License. QGIS lets you browse and create map data on your computer. It supports many common spatial data formats (e.g. ESRI ShapeFile, geotiff). QGIS supports plugins to do things like display tracks from your GPS. QGIS is Open Source software and its free of cost (download here). We welcome contributions from our user community in the form of code contributions, bug fixes, bug reports, contributed documentation, advocacy and supporting other users on our mailing lists and forums. Financial contributions are also welcome.</para><para>You can also <ulink url="https://qgis.org/downloads/qgis-api-doc.zip">download</ulink> this documentation or a <ulink url="qgis.qch">Qt help file</ulink> for offline use.</para><para>There is also a <ulink url="https://qgis.org/pyqgis/master">Python version of the documentation</ulink> available.</para></sect1>
<sect1 id="index_1index_APIStability">
<title>Earlier versions of the API</title>
<para>See <ref refid="api_break" kindref="compound">Backwards Incompatible Changes</ref> for information about incompatible changes to API between releases.</para><para>Earlier versions of the documentation are also available on the QGIS website: <ulink url="https://qgis.org/api/3.2">3.2</ulink>, <ulink url="https://qgis.org/api/3.0">3.0</ulink>, <ulink url="https://qgis.org/api/2.18">2.18 (LTR)</ulink>, <ulink url="https://qgis.org/api/2.14">2.14 (LTR)</ulink>, <ulink url="https://qgis.org/api/2.12">2.12</ulink>, <ulink url="https://qgis.org/api/2.10">2.10</ulink>, <ulink url="https://qgis.org/api/2.8">2.8 (LTR)</ulink>, <ulink url="https://qgis.org/api/2.6">2.6</ulink>, <ulink url="https://qgis.org/api/2.4">2.4</ulink>, <ulink url="https://qgis.org/api/2.2">2.2</ulink>, <ulink url="https://qgis.org/api/2.0">2.0</ulink>, <ulink url="https://qgis.org/api/1.8">1.8</ulink>, <ulink url="https://qgis.org/api/1.7">1.7</ulink> and <ulink url="https://qgis.org/api/1.6">1.6</ulink></para></sect1>
<sect1 id="index_1qgsquick_docs">
<title>QgsQuick library documentation</title>
<para>See <ref refid="qgsquick" kindref="compound">QGIS Quick Documentation</ref> for information about QGIS Quick (QML) components library</para></sect1>
<sect1 id="index_1index_maillist">
<title>Mailing Lists</title>
<para>For support we encourage you to join our <ulink url="https://qgis.org/en/site/forusers/support.html#mailing-lists">mailing lists</ulink> for users and developers.</para></sect1>
<sect1 id="index_1index_bugs">
<title>Bug Reporting</title>
<para>If you think you have found a bug, please report it using our <ulink url="https://issues.qgis.org/projects/qgis">bug tracker</ulink>. When reporting bugs, please include some contact information in case we need help with replicating your issue.</para></sect1>
<sect1 id="index_1index_ircchannel">
<title>IRC channel</title>
<para>Some QGIS users and developers can also often be found in the <ulink url="irc://irc.freenode.net/#qgis">#qgis</ulink> IRC channel on irc.freenode.net.</para><para> </para></sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
